viamichelin.co.uk 2017-11-17

# Privacy | ViaMichelin

### **Introduction**

Michelin Travel Partner, a wholly-owned subsidiary of the Michelin Group that is a French company with share capital of €11,288,880, registered with the Nanterre Trade and Companies Registry under number 433 677 721, whose registered office is located at 27 Cours de l’Ile Seguin, 92105 Boulogne Billancourt, France, designs, develops and markets Michelin tourism products and digital mobility assistance services.

This personal data protection charter applies to all websites (hereinafter ‘Websites’) and mobile and tablet applications (hereinafter ‘Applications’), and/or the local variations thereof that Michelin Travel Partner publishes, and which are listed below:

  * [ViaMichelin](http://viamichelin.fr/) (Websites and Applications); 
  * [Michelin Travel](http://voyage.michelin.fr/) (Websites and Applications);
  * [the MICHELIN guide](https://www.guide.michelin.com/) (Websites and Applications);
  * [Michelin Plaques](http://plaques.guide.michelin.fr/) (Websites) ;
  * [Michelin Days](https://www.days.michelin.fr/) (Websites);
  * [Michelin Camping ](https://camping.michelin.fr/)(Websites);
  * [Michelin Business Solutions](http://business-solutions.travel.michelin.fr/) (Websites).

Michelin Travel Partner has carried out with the French data protection authority the formalities required prior to processing personal data collected using the Websites and Applications.

This personal data protection charter is subject to change in accordance with the statutory and regulatory environment.

###  **1.  ** **Type of data collected**

When you use the Websites and/or Applications, certain data, in particular personal data within the meaning of article 2 of the French Data Protection Act of 6 January 1978, as amended, may be collected directly from you by Michelin Travel Partner or may be sent to us by a partner social network when you register or connect to that network. When you register or connect using social networking data, you are notified of the information that the relevant social network sends to us and we seek your prior approval before this information is sent.

Michelin Travel Partner may also receive personal data about you from other sales partners, who must warrant that they are authorised to collect and transmit such data.

Michelin Travel Partner collects and processes only data that is strictly necessary for the purpose for which they are processed. Michelin Travel Partner shall take all appropriate measures to ensure that the personal data it processes is accurate and, if necessary, updated.

###  **2.  ** **Data collection purposes**

Michelin Travel Partner processes data for a clear, legitimate and specific purpose.

Your data will be processed for the following main purposes:

  * managing your ‘My Michelin Account’ and your registration and connection to Michelin Days, and providing the services that they both offer;
  * managing your order;
  * managing and processing your requests;
  * if applicable, managing your participation in promotions or contests;
  * creating a customer database for the purposes of customer loyalty actions, sales prospecting, promotions, behavioural studies and/or marketing, in accordance with prevailing regulations;
  * ensuring that Michelin Travel Partner is in compliance with its legal obligations as the publisher of online electronic communication services for the public.

###  **3.  ** **User information  **

In accordance with the French Data Protection Act of 6 January 1978, as amended, Michelin Travel Partner is required to inform you of the processing of personal data that it carries out.

Therefore, Michelin Travel Partner will clearly inform you each time it collects personal data and, in particular, will tell you:

  * the identity of the data controller;
  * the purpose for which your personal data is collected;
  * whether responses requested are optional or mandatory, and the possible consequences of failing to reply;
  * that you have the right to query, access, modify, rectify, delete and, on legitimate grounds, oppose the use of your personal data, and the procedures for exercising such rights, and the right to provide instructions for your data after your death;
  * if transfers of personal data are planned to any country that is not a European Union Member State;
  * the period for which the data will be held, or where that information is unable to be provided, the criteria used to determine that period.

###  **4.  ** **Recipients of data collected**

Michelin Travel Partner will share your personal data only with specific authorised recipients. The recipients of your personal data include the following:

  * relevant Michelin Travel Partner services;
  * the following Michelin group companies (hereinafter ‘Michelin group companies’);
    *  **Manufacture des Pneumatiques Michelin** , Place des Carmes Déchaux, 63040 Clermont-Ferrand Cedex 9, France, a French _société en commandite par actions_ (limited partnership with shares) with share capital of €504,000,004, Clermont-Ferrand Trade and Companies Registry No. 855 200 507;
    *  **Michelin España Portugal  **S.A., Avda. de los Encuartes, 19 Tres Cantos, 28760 Madrid, Spain, CIF A20003570;
    *  **Michelin Italiana** , S.p.A., corso Romania 546, Turin, Italy;
    *  **Michelin Belux** , Brusselsesteenweg 494 1, 1731 Zellik, Belgium – Brussels Commercial Registry No. BE 400.906.146;
    *  **Michelin Tyre Public Limited Company** , Campbell Road, Stoke-On-Trent, Staffordshire, ST4 4EY, Company No. 00084559;
    *  **Michelin Reifenwerke AG & Co.** KGaA, Michelinstraße 4, 76185 Karlsruhe;
  * if applicable, Michelin Travel Partner subcontractors;
  * if applicable, Michelin Travel Partner partners and parties that have contracted with Michelin Travel Partner;
  * other users who are members of the Websites and Applications in the case of data whose publication you have authorised.

Michelin Travel Partner requires Michelin group companies, as well as, where applicable, its subcontractors, partners and parties with whom it contracts, to undertake to implement all necessary precautions, in light of the nature of the data and the risks created by its processing, to maintain the security of the data and, in particular, to prevent the data from being altered or damaged and to prevent access thereto by unauthorised third parties. In the event that the transmission of data to companies in the Michelin group, sub-contractors, partners or parties that have contracted with Michelin Travel Partner involves the transfer of your personal data to a country that is not a member of the European Union, Michelin Travel Partner shall ensure that the transfer is protected by mechanisms and guarantees that comply with prevailing regulations.

Michelin Travel Partner hereby informs you that it will transmit the information it holds, including personal data it has processed, pursuant to a request for such data that is made in accordance with the laws in force by any court or other government authority authorised by law.

### 5\. Transfers outside the EU

As part of the administration we carry out to ‘My Michelin Account’, please note that personal data associated with this account is likely to be transferred to our service provider in the United States.

Transfers of data outside the group are protected by agreements that contain the model European Commission clauses for non-EU sub-contractors in order to guarantee a level of protection that is at least similar to the level provided in your country of residence.

###  **6.  ** **Comments fields**

Certain pages of the Websites and/or Applications allow users to draft and transmit specific requests to Michelin Travel Partner (contact forms, error, reports, etc.) using forms they can complete as they choose.

The information that users transmit to Michelin Travel Partner in such manner should never contain personal data, and should always be pertinent, restrained and objective in light of the subject matter in question.

###  **7\. Cookies**

Michelin Travel Partner collects data concerning the manner in which you use our websites and our applications so that it can offer a better service to visitors and users of those websites and applications. It does this through the use of cookies and other trackers, which are files stored by your internet browser on your hard drive when you visit a website or use an application. To find out more about our cookie policy.

###  **8\. Minors**

The Michelin Travel Partner websites and applications are not, in general, intended for people under the age of eighteen (18). If you are under eighteen, please do not transmit personal information without your parents’ consent.

###  **9\. Newsletters**

Users of the Websites and/or Applications may register and receive Michelin Travel Partner newsletters by providing their email address using the form available for such purpose on the relevant Website and/or Application.

The information that Michelin Travel Partner collects in this way will be used solely to manage your newsletter registrations and to send the newsletters to you.

You can manage your newsletter registrations from your ‘My Michelin Account’ personal account.

In accordance with the law, you have the right to access and rectify the information about you and, on legitimate grounds, to oppose its use. You may exercise this right by sending an email to:  [privacy@tp.michelin.com](mailto:contact-fr@tp.michelin.com).

###  **10.  ** **Data storage  **

Michelin Travel Partner will store your data only for the time necessary to carry out the operations for which they were collected, and in compliance with the laws in force.

###  **11.  ** **Security**

Michelin Travel Partner ensures the security of your personal data through a robust data protection system that uses physical and logical security measures.

If all or part of personal data processing is subcontracted, Michelin Travel Partner will impose personal data confidentiality and security obligations on its subcontractors, by contract, in accordance with article 35 of the French Data Protection Act of 6 January 1978, as amended.

###  **12.  ** **User rights**

In accordance with the French Data Protection Act of 6 January 1978, as amended, you have a right to query, access, modify, rectify, delete and, on legitimate grounds, oppose the use of your personal data, and the right to provide instructions for your data after your death.

To exercise these rights, simply send us a letter, enclosing a copy of an identity document, by email to [privacy@tp.michelin.com](mailto:contact-fr@tp.michelin.com) or by post to the following address:  **Michelin Travel Partner, Service Client,  **27 Cours de l’Ile Seguin, 92105 Boulogne-Billancourt Cedex, France.

###  **13.  ** **Contact us**

This charter is intended to evolve over time, and we undertake to supplement it in order to meet your needs and expectations.

Therefore, we welcome your questions and suggestions about this charter. Please send us your comments using the ['Contact us’](http://info.viamichelin.com/web/contact-us) section.

If you have other questions, please refer to the menu at the foot of each page (‘footer’) of our Websites. Perhaps we have already answered your question.

 _(version 15.2 – August 2017)_
